<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>realm</title>
    <link>https://smaran-m.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on realm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 15:53:03 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smaran-m.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making a Smash Clone</title>
      <link>https://smaran-m.github.io/blog/dunjin1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 15:53:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smaran-m.github.io/blog/dunjin1/</guid>
      <description>I have a lot of nostalgia for games that I have never played. You know those fake games that they would put on in an episode of a 90s sitcom or something which had generic fantasy tropes, but nothing identifiable enough to get them sued? Or that episode where characters dress up to play D&amp;amp;D (which I found out way too late that no one does irl)? I miss those games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dungeoncrawler</title>
      <link>https://smaran-m.github.io/projects/dungeoncrawler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 03:27:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smaran-m.github.io/projects/dungeoncrawler/</guid>
      <description>Dunjin (working title) is a WIP multiplayer platform fighter using Godot ver 3.5.3. The game is currently in a prototype state.
Motivation I wanted to make the TTRPG combat experience more enjoyable, using medieval themes but a real time battle system that allows for a high skill ceiling. I&amp;rsquo;m using a smash archetype for the character controller, but plan to have this as both a single-player and multiplayer game. This is currently a solo project: I did all the art and code, but the parallax background behind the windows was sourced from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ripples</title>
      <link>https://smaran-m.github.io/projects/ripples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 16:31:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smaran-m.github.io/projects/ripples/</guid>
      <description>Ripples Live Demo Check out sammi.sh. This also functions as my creative project website, and will be updated occasionally.
Motivations I&amp;rsquo;m still obsessed with ASCII art and textmode, but recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to learn a bit more about procedural content. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into simple procedural animations with inverse kinematics for an independent game project, and thought I&amp;rsquo;d showcase some of that over on my creative project website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maptisse: A Tilemap Generator</title>
      <link>https://smaran-m.github.io/projects/gridshade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:20:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smaran-m.github.io/projects/gridshade/</guid>
      <description>Usage  build with dotnet build run with dotnet run click and drag to fill in squares select tileset with dropdown menu generate!  Features  doodle around and generate tilemaps that work great for games and TTRPGs generates almost instantaneously, make quick changes on the fly save and load grid states as JSON files edit tileset at will in any image editor of your choice (resources/tilesets/)  Motivations So I played around with an evolution sim in python back in high-school, but never got past the stage of procedurally generated levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image-to-ASCII</title>
      <link>https://smaran-m.github.io/projects/i2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 23:25:02 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smaran-m.github.io/projects/i2a/</guid>
      <description>Usage  install PIL: pip install pillow run the script images will be output to ./out  Examples supports different quality outputs: Motivations A few years ago, I found out about donut.c which was equal parts artistry and wizardry to me. I really liked the look of it, growing up surrounded by ASCII art on obscure forums.
Recently, reminded of this, I wrote a script to automatically convert images to similar kinds of art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello!</title>
      <link>https://smaran-m.github.io/blog/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 13:47:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smaran-m.github.io/blog/hello/</guid>
      <description>my name is Smaran. I am a first-year MSCS student based in Atlanta, GA 🐝. I like making well designed technology to help people work and feel better. While my specialization is in systems and multimedia, I also like working on tools and testing - I ESPECIALLY like when these areas mix.
browse my code! my github
look at my art! my portfolio
hire me! my resume.
this is my website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
